# Josias Matos Batista

Technical Support Analyst | Web Developer

Phone: +1 (809) 392-5923 | Email: <u>Josiasmatosb@gmail.com</u> | LinkedIn: <u>Josias Matos B.</u>

## **Professional Summary**

With over three years of experience as a Technical Support Analyst and a strong track record in client-facing roles, I bring a valuable combination of technical expertise and effective leadership skills. Notable achievements include my rapid promotion at Altice USA to train new hires on technical support processes and procedures within three months of joining. I have also earned a reputation as the go-to team member for simplifying complex technical information for high-profile clients, consistently receiving praise for making intricate transactions easily understandable. My unwavering commitment to exceptional customer service and my skill in bridging the gap between technical complexities and client needs make me a valuable asset in any client-centric environment.

## **Technical Skill Set**

- Databases: Oracle SQL Developer, phpMyadmin, MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL.
- Technologies / Tools : AngularJS, JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML5, CSS, Postman, Git, GitHub
- **OS**: Windows, Linux.

# **Work Experience**

#### **Technical Support Analyst**

November 2022 – Present

**Thryv,** Santo Domingo, Dominican Republic.

## **Responsibilities:**

- Investigates and resolves complex inquiries and problems associated with operating, order, fulfillment and billing systems.
- Documents and assigns issues to development teams. Researches, investigates, and analyzes issues which includes "steps to reproduce" for multiple applications. Determines severity of the problem. Monitors timeline of corrections and escalates when appropriate.
- Ensures timely communications to all impacted teams. Fields questions and requests and communicates resolution in a timely and thorough manner.

# **Customer Product Support**

February 2022 to May 2022

Verizon at (NewTech Software, SA.), Santo Domingo, Dominican Republic.

## **Responsibilities:**

- Created and followed up on tickets of issues related to website, resulting in a decrease of customer complaints by 25%.
- Successfully resolved an average of 20 tickets per day, ensuring that all customers had their issues addressed in a timely manner.
- Followed up with customers after issue was resolved to ensure satisfaction and address any lingering concerns, which resulted in a 10% increase in customer retention.

# **Customer Technical Support**

Altice USA at (Advensus), Santo Domingo, Dominican Republic.

#### **Responsibilities:**

- Successfully troubleshoot home services for 50+ customers per day, meeting, or exceeding company metrics for customer satisfaction.
- Trained new hires on company's technical support process and procedures.
- Reduced number of escalated calls by 15% through implementation of new trouble-shooting methods.

#### **Machine Support**

**June 2015 to May 2017** 

Peniel stationery and bookstore, Barahona, Dominican Republic

## **Responsibilities:**

- Maintained computer operating system for 50+ machines, ensuring peak efficiency for users.
- Maintained copy machines, reducing downtime by 35%.
- Successfully completed training in machine maintenance and upkeep.

## **Education & Certifications**

# IT Technician (High school Diploma)

Technical High School Dr. Federico Enriquez and Carvajal Graduated in (2015)

#### **Computer Science (Bachelor's degree)**

Autonomous University of Santo Domingo (UASD) Dominican Republic. Expected to accomplish in December 2023

## **Oracle Certification Program**

Oracle Certified Foundations Associate, Oracle Cloud Infrastructure. Accomplish in January 2022

# Free Code Academy Program

GCSA: GNU Certified System Administrator Accomplish in July 2021

# LinkedIn Learning

IT Support Specialist Accomplish in May 2021

#### **Talendig**

BootCamp on FullStack Development Accomplish in December 2022